streetcar.co.uk 2016-11-25

# Privacy Policy – Zipcar

## r-e-s-p-e-c-t!

**Zipcar, Inc. ("Zipcar")** and its subsidiaries and affiliates (also referred to as we," "us," "our" or "Zipcar group") **respects your privacy.** This privacy policy describes the personal information we collect from you and how we use that information. This privacy policy covers both our collection and use of information when you use zipcar.com, zipcar.ca, zipcar.co.uk and their related mobile sites and applications (our "Sites"), as well as the kinds of information we collect when you join Zipcar and use our services. This privacy policy does not apply to other Internet or mobile sites or applications even if accessed via our Sites. If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policy, please contact us in one of the ways provided below. By submitting your personal information to us, you consent to Zipcar's use and disclosure of your personal information as set forth in this privacy notice. If you do not agree with the terms of this privacy notice, please do not submit any personal information to Zipcar. If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy notice, please contact us in one of the ways provided below. This privacy notice is incorporated into, and part of, the Member Contract and the Terms of Use, which governs zipcar.com, zipcar.ca and zipcar.co.uk

Zipcar has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program covers the website www.zipcar.com and does not cover any mobile applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@zipcar.com](mailto:privacy@zipcar.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

## what is personal information?

Personal information means information that identifies you as an individual, or that we can combine with readily available information to identify you as an individual.

## what personal information we collect and how we use it

The principle purposes for which we collect and store your personal and financial information are to process your application, allow you to reserve and use our vehicles, authorise payment, bill you, respond to your enquiries, improve our products and services and maintain your account with us.

**When you use our Sites,** our servers automatically log certain information about your use of our Sites, such as your IP address, your browser type, operating system, browser language and service provider. We also collect information about your activities on our Sites, such as the pages you visit or the ads or links you click on. The first time you visit one of our Sites, Zipcar assigns you a unique number, which is stored in one or more cookies on your computer's hard drive. These cookies help us distinguish new visitors from returning visitors and enable us to measure the effectiveness of content on the Sites and refine and tailor that content to suit our visitors' interests. If you have joined Zipcar or provided other personal information about yourself (for example, if you send us an email), your cookie ID can be associated with you personally. To learn more about cookies and how Zipcar customises the content and offers for you, please see **"Advertising and Personalised Content"** below and our **Cookie Policy.**

**Zipcar collects information that you voluntarily submit to us,** which could include your name, email address, postal address, telephone number, or a picture of you or identifying documents. This also includes information in your profile or information you provide to us via an email, or similar message, telephone call, or by other means. Your telephone calls and other correspondence with us may be recorded or monitored for quality control, training and similar purposes. By using these communication methods you are consenting to the recording or monitoring of your calls and communications with Zipcar.

**If you apply to join Zipcar,** we collect information such as personal and financial information as you proceed through the stages of our application process, membership agreement and reservation process. In addition to your name and contact information, we will also collect your driver's license number and the jurisdiction in which you are registered, credit card or other payment information and other identifying information. We may also collect information such as your driving record from regulatory bodies where you live, or from third parties. We use this information to process your application and, if you are approved, for the purposes described below. Additionally, we may also use this information to monitor or detect fraud, theft or abuse of our service.

**If you join Zipcar and use our services,** we collect information about your searches for vehicles, reservations (dates, times, locations, etc.), your use of the Zipcar service (return time, mileage, accidents, etc.) and other information stored on or reported by your computer or other mobile device which may, for example, include its motion, location and/or internet protocol address, its unique device identifier, hardware or software used, network accessed, information about other applications used, or communications/contact information of other individuals which may be available. We use this information to provide and optimise services for you, including, for example, billing you, responding to your enquiries, providing and improving our products and services, maintaining your account with us, to personalising your Zipcar experience (i.e., by understanding your preferences), and providing content and promotional offers. To learn more about how Zipcar customises the content and offers you please see "Advertising and Personalised Content" below. From time to time, we may send marketing or other communications to you. To unsubscribe from our newsletters please use the opt out in the account settings page and our **Cookie Policy.**

**Zipcars may be equipped with Global Positioning System (GPS) vehicle tracking technology and anti-theft technology** that uses GPS. GPS is a network of satellites that allows us to determine the location (latitude and longitude) of Zipcars during your reservation. Additionally, Zipcars may also have an on-board device that may monitor the state of the vehicle from moment to moment, including its location during your reservation. This information is transmitted to Zipcar and stored. Zipcar uses this information for a variety of important purposes. For example, we monitor or store vehicle or GPS data to help you find a car you have reserved, to assist with roadside assistance, to ensure that a car is available at the place and time you have reserved, and to locate lost or stolen Zipcars.

**Zipcars may be equipped with telematics data tracking technology** (this section applies only to Members who accepted the Privacy Policy on or after 13 April 2016). The use of vehicle telematics is becoming increasingly common in the automotive sector and it enables companies like Zipcar to better understand how vehicles are being used, ultimately leading to better service availability for members. The telematics data tracking technology allows us to monitor driver behaviour of members, which encourages responsible and safe driving and will assist reducing fleet and operational costs. This is extremely useful if vehicles are stolen or involved in an accident, as the vehicles can be recovered swiftly, accidents can be prevented and insurance claims settled based on facts. In addition, at an anonymous and aggregated level, insight can be obtained about Zipcar usage overall.

**Refer a Friend.** If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about Zipcar, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address or telephone number. We may send your friend one or more messages inviting your friend to join Zipcar. Zipcar stores this information for the sole purpose of sending these communications and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at [privacy@zipcar.com](mailto:privacy@zipcar.com) to request that we remove this information from our database; however, if someone else subsequently refers the same friend, the friend's contact information may be stored again.

Zipcar work with Mention Me, a 3rd party referral provider, to ensure the best referral process possible. In order to facilitate Mention Me referrals we share some basic data with them in order that they can identify and reward the correct participants. This data will in no way be used for other purposes besides the fulfilment of your referral.

## children's privacy

We do not knowingly solicit or collect individually identifying information from children under the age of 13.

## where we hold personal information

Zipcar maintains servers within the European Union and in the United States of America. Please note that the laws governing the processing of personal information in the United States of America may not be the same as they are in Europe or Canada. By joining Zipcar and using our services, you consent to the transfer of your personal and financial information outside of the European Economic Area and Canada, as applicable, for the purposes described in this privacy policy.

Zipcar complies with all applicable data protection laws regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. 

## to what third parties might we transfer personal information?

Except as described in this privacy policy, Zipcar will not share your personal information with third parties outside the Zipcar group unless it is necessary to provide the Zipcar service, fulfil a transaction you have requested, or in other circumstances with your consent. We do however disclose your personal information within the Zipcar affiliated group and to contractors, advisors, consultants and service providers acting on our behalf or under our instructions, including for purposes relating to the operation, maintenance, administration, improvement, and oversight of our services, Sites and advertising services, or to fulfil your requests for information or service. If you apply for Zipcar membership, some of the information you supply must necessarily be shared with regulatory bodies and/or service providers we utilise to obtain your driving record and or other personal information. In addition, if you are associated or affiliated with another, primary account (for example, if you are an associate member or affiliated with a business's or university's account), the business or university will generally have access to certain information regarding your account or use of our services.

We may disclose your personal information in connection with a corporate transaction, proceeding, or reorganization involving the business activities for which the information is maintained. In the event that ownership of Zipcar or its business was to change as a result of a merger, acquisition or transfer to another company, your personal information may be transferred.

Zipcar may disclose your personal information, including location/GPS data/telematics tracking data, in response to legal process (for example, a court order, search warrant or subpoena) or requests from law enforcement or regulatory authorities; in other circumstances in which Zipcar believes the Sites, the Zipcar service or our vehicles are being or have been used in violation of the applicable law or otherwise in the commission of a crime; when we have a good faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the safety of you or another person; or when necessary to protect the rights or property of Zipcar or third parties.

## independent licensees

Reservations of certain Zipcar vehicles may be operated by an independent licensee not owned or controlled by Zipcar, and in those instances this privacy notice does not apply. Each independent licensee may collect personal information and use the personal information for its own purposes. Zipcar does not control the independent licensee's use of personal information. For credit card transactions, the independent licensee, not Zipcar, may collect and process credit card information and receive payment for the Zipcar services. In this case, the independent licensee is subject to the merchant rules of the credit card processors it selects. This privacy notice also does not apply to any independent licensee's website. These licensees may also use email campaigns and other methods of telephone, electronic and direct mail solicitation without our consent or knowledge and are solely responsible for their content and methods of identifying and contacting addressees.

## advertising and personalised content

Zipcar may use personal information to present offers to you on our behalf and on behalf of business partners, but we do not share information that personally identifies you with those parties for their independent marketing purposes. **If you do not want us to send you promotional emails, please adjust your settings on the "contact me" tab on the "my stuff" page.**

Zipcar may also use third party ad network providers and other service providers to help present customised content and offers across various platforms, including the Internet or our Sites. These providers use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer to help present, better target, and measure the effectiveness of their content and advertisements, using data gathered over time and across their networks of web pages to determine or predict the characteristics and preferences of their audience. We may share certain non-personal information about you (such as age and zip code) with certain ad network and service providers to help them deliver more relevant content and advertisements through their networks. **The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by content and ad network providers is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours.**

Cookies are text files that are placed in the browser on your computer or mobile device, and that can be used to help recognize you on the Zipcar Sites. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. We use session cookies to maintain session state and user identity. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. We use persistent cookies to help remember user preferences. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your browser's "help" file.

You can control browser cookies through your browser's settings. You can control Flash cookies via the Macromedia Flash application on your computer, or by going to the [Macromedia Flash Player website](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html), which allows you to view, modify, and delete Flash cookies. You may delete cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you reject all browser or flash cookies, however, some areas of our Sites may not function well or at all.

Third party advertisers or service providers we use or provide information to may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies in connection with offers, content, and services offered through the Zipcar Sites, including to help operate ad networks. Please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/index.asp) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) websites for additional information about various providers and the options they may offer.

The use of cookies or similar devices by partners, affiliates, and advertisers or service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Our Sites includes links to other websites or mobile applications whose privacy practices may differ from those of Zipcar. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit or mobile application that you use.

We do not respond to Web browser 'do not track' signals at this time. We await the result of work by the policy community and industry to determine when such a response is appropriate and what form it should take. We do allow you to exercise choice regarding the collection of information by third parties about your online activities over time and across certain third-party Web sites or online services for online interest based advertising purposes by going to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or [http://www.aboutads.info/choices.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

## how may i review and correct my personal information?

Zipcar is committed to providing you with reasonable and practical access to your information to allow you the opportunity to identify inaccuracies. If you are a member of Zipcar, you can review and correct personal information by clicking on the "my stuff" button and navigating through the "my account," "my reservations" and "my statement" pages. If you would like to access, delete and/or correct other personal information held by Zipcar, please contact us in one of the ways provided below and we will respond to your request within 30 days. If Zipcar is informed of any inaccuracy we will make the appropriate corrections when commercially practicable. If you are a resident of the United Kingdom, under the Data Protection Act 1998 (as amended) you have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you and have any inaccuracies corrected (we will charge a reasonable fee for such information requests and require you to prove your identity with 2 pieces of approved identification).

Please contact us if you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may also retain and use your information in order to make promotional offers to you as described under "advertising and personalised content" above, unless you have opted out of receiving such communications.

## what security measures are used to protect my personal information?

Zipcar has established safeguards, such as SSL encryption, to help prevent unauthorised access to or misuse of your personal information, but cannot guarantee that your personal information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this privacy policy (for example, as a result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate applicable law or the policies of Zipcar and its affiliated providers). We use a password to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your personal information. It is your responsibility to safeguard your password, which you should never disclose to a third party. If you contact us by phone, we will ask you to verify certain information related to your account before providing any access to personal information.

From time to time, we may need to move technology platform and related information systems infrastructure and software, which we will do in accordance with applicable laws.

## how might this privacy policy be changed?

We may change this privacy policy from time to time, so it is advisable to review it frequently. Changes to this privacy policy will be announced on our website or through similar means and all amended terms shall take effect no less than seven (7) days after announcement.

## contact information

If you have questions about our handling of personal information, you may write to us at [privacy@zipcar.com](mailto:privacy@zipcar.com) or at one of the addresses below.

It is important you take the time to read, understand and accept the terms of this privacy policy. We will contact you by email, telephone, sms or other such means to confirm you have read, understood and accepted this privacy policy.

## corporate identity

Zipcar, Inc. is located at 35 Thomson Place in Boston, Massachusetts 02210 USA.

Zipcar Canada Inc.'s registered office is at 77 King Street West, Toronto-Dominion Centre, Suite 400, Toronto, Ontario M5K 0A1.

Zipcar (UK) Ltd is located at Melbury House, 51 Wimbledon Hill Rd, London, SW19 7QW (company number 04525217), and, if you joined Zipcar in the UK, is the data controller of your information.

Zipcar Austria GmbH is located at Erdbergstraße 189-193, 1030 Vienna, Austria

Catalunya Carsharing, S.A. (Avancar) is located at Travessera de Gràcia, 342, 8º 6ª, 08025, Barcelona, Spain.

This privacy policy was last revised in April 2016.
